<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[OFM]]></title><description><![CDATA[My journey battling Ocular Melanoma.]]></description><link>https://mcornell.github.io/OFM</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 11:43:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mcornell.github.io/OFM/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Radiation Camping]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Hello all.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It&#8217;s been a little over 24 hours since I checked into a hotel in Philadelphia after my first surgery.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On Sunday, I flew out to Philadelpha. My parents picked me up and I slept in the bed of my youth.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On Monday morning, I was at Wills Eye Center at 7am. I was trying to register, but the staff didn&#8217;t know I was supposed to be there. I guess that&#8217;s what happens when the doctors running the place make promises over the weekend. Remember this when your upper management makes a promise that you don&#8217;t know about. The staff was awesome trying to help me out. They didn&#8217;t publically bitch to me about how the docs didn&#8217;t communicate well.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It took a good hour to get Ohio State to send over all of the scans and pictures over to Wills. Some of them were useful, some were not. Wills basically did the same pictures and scans with different equipment over a 10 hour stay. Yes 10 hours. No joke.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We left Wills with a plan for surgery on Thursday and a need of getting blood work done and a physical. That&#8217;s sort of tough since I&#8217;m not in Ohio. Fortunately, I was able to get these tasks done on Tuesday with the help of Wills staff.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Meanwhile, my wife was driving from Columbus to Philadelphia on Tuesday. She couldn&#8217;t have had worse luck. it took her 11 hours because of rain in Columbus not getting her to Zanesville until 9:15. A good hour delay. Accidents on the turnpike in Philly also killed a good hour of time. She got to the house at 6pm with the kids and dog.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>One thing that was very smart was finding a way to bring the dog. He&#8217;s 11 months old, and although it was a long miserable anxious trip for him, he&#8217;s enjoying the larger yard at Grandma&#8217;s house and the kids are enjoying spending time with him. I also enjoyed walking him with my wife.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Wednesday, we relaxed as best we could, since Lori and I were getting up at 5 to drive into Philly and check in for surgery by 7 am. Before I knew it, I was meeting with the docs, and wheeling into surgery. I dont even remember counting backwards.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We then drove over to the hotel, got checked in, and sorted out. She grabbed my meds from CVS and spent the night here, which was nice, even though she had to stay far away.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The docs from Wills stopped by at 4 to see how I was doing and answer questions.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Otherwise, I&#8217;m treating this like a campout. This thing gets taken out early on Monday morning, and then the plan is to drive home early Tuesday morning.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Be well!</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://mcornell.github.io/OFM/2017/04/14/Radiation-Camping.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mcornell.github.io/OFM/2017/04/14/Radiation-Camping.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Ocular_Melanoma]]></category><category><![CDATA[Wills_Eye]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cornell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Time To Fly]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>My, how things can change in 48 hours.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Yesterday, Friday 4/7, I spent about 6 hours at Ohio State&#8217;s Havener Eye Institute (<a href="http://eye.osu.edu/" class="bare">http://eye.osu.edu/</a>). I got some awesome scans and pictures of my eye done. I also found out the bastard was quite a bit larger than I thought. Also, much like the scene in Predator, it was one ugly SOB.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I met some awesome doctors who, unwillingly, made me feel like I had accomplished little in my career. My doc is just 2 years older than me (hooray public records) and she is one of 4, people in the Ohio who know what they are doing with this sort of cancer.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And all I&#8217;ve done is write software. Yes, I&#8217;ve writted software to help people manage their finances and help customers, but not to save lives. But I digress.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>They came up with a plan, which was similar to what was outlined before. They would order a radioactive plaque. What&#8217;s interesting is how it&#8217;s placed on the eye. It will be placed attached to the outside of the eye, where the tumor is. So basically it won&#8217;t be visible to anyone, because it&#8217;s effectively by the eye socket. This link explains this quite well (<a href="https://eyecancer.com/eye-cancer/treatments/eye-and-vision-sparing-radiation-therapy-for-intraocular-tumors/" class="bare">https://eyecancer.com/eye-cancer/treatments/eye-and-vision-sparing-radiation-therapy-for-intraocular-tumors/</a>)</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So at OSU, they said, surgery to put this thing in on Thursday, take it out on Monday. Should be back to work two weeks later. Wow! Except, they couldn&#8217;t start surgery until mid-May due to doctor schedule and the amount of time to get the plaque. I asked if there was any way to move faster.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So the docs at OSU sent a note to Wills Eye Center in Philly (<a href="https://www.willseye.org/ocular-oncology-service" class="bare">https://www.willseye.org/ocular-oncology-service</a>). Wills is a good choice for me because of family across the river in NJ. It also happens to be "the" place to get this procedure done.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Today I got a phone call around 5pm. I&#8217;ve been accepted into Wills. Show up at 8am on Monday. I used what little frequent flyer miles i have to get a one way ticket to Philly. My wife and kids will drive out on Tuesday.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This adventure keeps getting crazier. But I said before, I&#8217;m going to kick this bastard&#8217;s ass. I really appreciate all of the support and well wishes.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I will continue to update as I have time. Thanks again.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://mcornell.github.io/OFM/2017/04/08/Time-To-Fly.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mcornell.github.io/OFM/2017/04/08/Time-To-Fly.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Ocular_Melanoma]]></category><category><![CDATA[Havener_Eye]]></category><category><![CDATA[Wills_Eye]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cornell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[This started as a GitHub Gist]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I stopped blogging ages ago, so this is the best way I could think of to log form this.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Yesterday, I went to the eye doctor because of messed up vision in my left eye. They told me I had a detatched retina and needed emergency surgery. I ran over to the surgeon and they began to examine me.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>They told me it&#8217;s not a detached retina, but an ocular melanoma.  You can read up on the details here: <a href="http://www.ocularmelanoma.org/disease.htm" class="bare">http://www.ocularmelanoma.org/disease.htm</a></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Basically I have a tumor at the back of my eye. Fluid is leaking into the eye which is causing the vision problem.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I don&#8217;t know how long it has been there, but it wasn&#8217;t found at my eye exam in July of 2016.  Tomorrow I go in to determine if the bastard has spread beyond my eye and determine a course of action.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Needless to say, I&#8217;m a bit on edge.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>However, I&#8217;m determined to kick the living hell out of this thing.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This is just the easiest way to let everyone on here know.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Thanks for listening.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://mcornell.github.io/OFM/2017/04/06/This-started-as-a-Git-Hub-Gist.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mcornell.github.io/OFM/2017/04/06/This-started-as-a-Git-Hub-Gist.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Ocular_Melanoma]]></category><category><![CDATA[Detached_Retina]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cornell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>