<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[OFM]]></title><description><![CDATA[My journey battling Ocular Melanoma.]]></description><link>https://mcornell.github.io/OFM</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 01:50:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mcornell.github.io/OFM/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Time To Fly]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>My, how things can change in 48 hours.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Yesterday, Friday 4/7, I spent about 6 hours at Ohio State&#8217;s Havener Eye Institute (<a href="http://eye.osu.edu/" class="bare">http://eye.osu.edu/</a>). I got some awesome scans and pictures of my eye done. I also found out the bastard was quite a bit larger than I thought. Also, much like the scene in Predator, it was one ugly SOB.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I met some awesome doctors who, unwillingly, made me feel like I had accomplished little in my career. My doc is just 2 years older than me (hooray public records) and she is one of 4, people in the Ohio who know what they are doing with this sort of cancer.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And all I&#8217;ve done is write software. Yes, I&#8217;ve writted software to help people manage their finances and help customers, but not to save lives. But I digress.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>They came up with a plan, which was similar to what was outlined before. They would order a radioactive plaque. What&#8217;s interesting is how it&#8217;s placed on the eye. It will be placed attached to the outside of the eye, where the tumor is. So basically it won&#8217;t be visible to anyone, because it&#8217;s effectively by the eye socket. This link explains this quite well (<a href="https://eyecancer.com/eye-cancer/treatments/eye-and-vision-sparing-radiation-therapy-for-intraocular-tumors/" class="bare">https://eyecancer.com/eye-cancer/treatments/eye-and-vision-sparing-radiation-therapy-for-intraocular-tumors/</a>)</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So at OSU, they said, surgery to put this thing in on Thursday, take it out on Monday. Should be back to work two weeks later. Wow! Except, they couldn&#8217;t start surgery until mid-May due to doctor schedule and the amount of time to get the plaque. I asked if there was any way to move faster.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So the docs at OSU sent a note to Wills Eye Center in Philly (<a href="https://www.willseye.org/ocular-oncology-service" class="bare">https://www.willseye.org/ocular-oncology-service</a>). Wills is a good choice for me because of family across the river in NJ. It also happens to be "the" place to get this procedure done.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Today I got a phone call around 5pm. I&#8217;ve been accepted into Wills. Show up at 8am on Monday. I used what little frequent flyer miles i have to get a one way ticket to Philly. My wife and kids will drive out on Tuesday.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This adventure keeps getting crazier. But I said before, I&#8217;m going to kick this bastard&#8217;s ass. I really appreciate all of the support and well wishes.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I will continue to update as I have time. Thanks again.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://mcornell.github.io/OFM/2017/04/08/Time-To-Fly.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mcornell.github.io/OFM/2017/04/08/Time-To-Fly.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Ocular_Melanoma]]></category><category><![CDATA[Havener_Eye]]></category><category><![CDATA[Wills_Eye]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Cornell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>